

SF BAY AREA, CA

408-216-3428

LE.NGUYEN.SY@GMAIL.COM

SYNLE.GITHUB.IO

LINKEDIN.COM/IN/SYLE1021

SUMMARY:

I'm Sy Le, a software engineer with a decade of experience at LinkedIn, Salesforce, and Yahoo. I built software for CRM, marketing automation, e-commerce, and monitoring platforms. My skills include JavaScript/TypeScript and React for front-end, and Node.js / RemixJS / Express for back-end development.

EDUCATION:

Master of Science, Software Engineering

San Jose State University

Graduated 2019

Graduated with Specialization in Cloud & Mobile Computing.
Bachelor of Science, Computer Science

San Jose State University

Graduated 2011

· Graduated Cum Laude with Specialization in Computer Graphics.

EXPERIENCE:

Staff Software Engineer at Linkedin

Sunnyvale, CA

From 05/2017 To Present

- As a Software Engineer at LinkedIn Enterprise Learning and Productivity Engineering, I leveraged my expertise in a wide range of technologies, including JavaScript, Ember, React, Node.js, Java, Spring Boot, Python, Flask, MySQL, Redis, and Azure to drive successful projects
- I provided expert guidance on UI frameworks and Azure DevOps CI/CD pipelines to drive success. My insights and expertise have helped the team streamline development and achieve outstanding results
- · Working on Linkedin Support Portal that manages customers' chats and offline cases on
- · Microsoft Dynamics365 CRM using C#, .NET Core, React and Microsoft Fluent UI
- As a Full-Stack Engineer Team Lead, I led the development of Nucleus, an end-to-end purchase flow automation platform, featuring a modern React-and-Redux Front-End and a robust Spring Boot back-end hosted on Azure, with integrations with ServiceNow and JIRA
- As a skilled full-stack developer, I have played a key role in redesigning Sendbloom's codebase, using the latest tools and technologies such as TypeScript, React, Redux, Node.js, Express, Redis, and MySQL. With my contributions, the platform is now more efficient, and user-friendly
- I integrated **Linkedin Learning** with Slideshare DocViewer, enabling end-to-end custom document content creation and viewing, which provided instructors with more options to organize and prepare their course outlines
- At the LinkedIn GOPs Expo 2017, I developed and presented the Room Booking Assistant (RoomBA), an innovative bot that intelligently identifies the best meeting rooms and books them on behalf of users, simplifying the process and saving valuable time

Senior Member of Technical Staff at Salesforce

San Francisco, CA

From 04/2015 To 05/2017

- Software Engineer for SalesforcelQ, and Aura using JavaScript, Angular, React, Salesforce Aura / Lightning, Node.js, Express, and Java
- Contributed significantly to SalesforcelQ Inbox Desktop, and providing leadership and mentorship to junior team members
- Built various prototypes, including an Inbox Desktop Email client with React and Electron and a Desktop Dialer with Twilio
- Won the SalesforcelQ Hackday Fall 2016 Most Creative award with the predictive email compose suggestion project and won the SalesforcelQ Hackday Spring 2017 Most Heroic award with the mass email project

Tech Yahoo, Software Dev Engineer at Yahoo Inc

Sunnvvale, CA

From 07/2014 To 04/2015

• As a Front-End engineer on the Yahoo Monitoring team, I worked on the redesign of the YAMAS 2.0 Dashboard using JavaScript, Angular, Node.js, and Express. Our redesign won an award at the internal Yahoo TechPulse 2014 conference. Additionally, I set up a CI and CD pipeline for Express back-end applications using Jenkins CI and Chef CD to streamline building and deployment

Software Engineer at eBay Inc

San Jose, CA

From 08/2013 To 07/2014

• As a Software Engineer on eBay Transaction Flow and Registration team, I implemented the responsive Guest Checkout Registration and integrated Selenium UI automation to extend UI integration test coverage to iPad and iPhone with JavaScript, Java and Spring MVC Framework

Software Engineer at eTrigue Inc

San Jose, CA

From 10/2011 To 08/2013

• As a Full-Stack Engineer, I used JavaScript, PHP, Node.js, C#, MySQL, Cassandra, and RabbitMQ to build key components of the eTrigue Demand Center. This includes Prospect List, Campaign Builder, ETL Jobs, and vendor integration with Cisco Webex and Citrix GoToWebinar

Software Engineer at MTSS

San Jose, CA

From 08/2010 To 10/2011

• As a Full-Stack Engineer, I built Clinic Tree, a clinic portal that includes features like patient record charting, appointment management, and a content management system. The portal was built using JavaScript, C#, and .NET

SIDE PROIECTS:

- **sqlui-native**: a cross-platform native desktop application built with Electron and React, which can manage various databases, including MySQL, PostgreSQL, MS SQL Server, Cassandra, MongoDB, and Redis. It supports Windows, Mac, and Linux operating systems
- display-dj: a cross-platform desktop application that allows users to adjust brightness for integrated and external monitors and switch to dark mode. It is compatible with Windows and Mac operating systems
- import-fixer: A deterministic npm executable module that removes duplicate or unused JavaScript/TypeScript imports
- Rest API Decorators: a TypeScript library that make writing API Client for Nodejs and Frontend simpler inspired by Square Retrofit library

SKILLS

• Front End: JavaScript, TypeScript, React, Redux, Reselect, React Query, Jest, Angular, Storybook, Sass, Grunt, Gulp, Puppeteer, Sinon